blognation.com 2013-08-05

# Privacy Policy - Blog Nation

**Effective Date: 12-09-12**

Blog Nation, owned by Reach Network, Inc., takes your privacy seriously. Please read the following to learn more about our Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about Blog Nation’s information collection practices, email us at [info@blognation.com], or contact us at 123 Lake Street S., Suite B-1, Kirkland, Washington.

Blog Nation has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html), including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Website, http:www.blognation.com.

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally though its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regaurding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at info@blognation.com. If you are not satistified with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint).

### WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS

This Privacy Policy covers Blog Nation's treatment of personal information that Blog Nation collects when you use or access the Blognation.com website (the “ **Site** ”) or when you use Blog Nation's services on the Site. As used herein, the term "personal information" means information that specifically identifies an individual (such as a username which can be your name, email address, or other account number), and information about that individual or his or her activities when directly linked to personally identifiable information. Personal information does not include "aggregate" information, which is data we collect about the use of the Site or about a group or category of users, products, or services from which individual identities or other personal information has been removed. This policy in no way restricts or limits our collection and use of aggregate information.

This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Blog Nation does not own or control, or to people that Blog Nation does not employ or manage.

### WHAT INFORMATION BLOG NATION COLLECTS

Blog Nation collects personal information when you directly provide it, such as when you register or claim your blog on the Site’s directories and maintain a profile associated with such blog.

Blog Nation also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, your computer's operating system, the browser type, the address of a referring website and your activity on the Site. Blog Nation may use log files, IP addresses, and browsing history and information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track a user's movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Some of this information may be shared with third parties. These third parties (except for the entity which "anonymizes the data") will only use or have access to the information in anonymized form.

Blog Nation may also collect certain information through the use of “cookies” and “pixel tags” as discussed below. 

### COOKIES AND PIXEL TAGS

Like many other websites, certain information may be automatically collected from you through the use of "cookies" or "pixel tags." A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie may be linked to personal information. Pixel tags (also known as clear gifs, web bugs or web beacons) are small, invisible graphic images that may be used on the Site or in emails relating to the Site to collect certain information and monitor user activity on the Site.  Advertisers and other third parties may also place cookies, clear gifs or other devices on your computer to collect nonpersonal information.

Cookies and pixel tags may be used, among other things, to enhance the user experience, serve advertising targeted to your interests, to better understand the usage and visitation of our Site and to gather information. For instance, by setting a cookie, the user would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while accessing the Site. Cookies can also enable Blog Nation or third parties to track and target the interests of users to enhance the user experience.  Nonpersonal information collected through cookies and pixel tags may be shared with and disclosed to third parties, who in turn may share and disclose such nonpersonal information. **_ _**

This policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, cookies in third party ads or services, and we encourage you to check the privacy policies of advertisers and/or ad services to learn about their use of cookies and other technology. 

If you wish to block, erase, or be warned of cookies, please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn about these functions. However, if a browser is set not to accept cookies or if a user rejects a cookie, some portions of the Site and the Service may not function properly.  For example, you may not be able to sign in and may not be able to access certain Site features or services

### LINKS TO WEBSITES

The Site contains links to other websites. Blog Nation is not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave the Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website to learn how such website collects and uses personally identifiable information.

### USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION BY BLOG NATION

In general, Blog Nation may use personal information to provide you with information, products or services you request, to process or respond to your requests or transactions, to inform you about other information, events, promotions, products or services we think will be of interest to you, to facilitate your use of, and Blog Nation's administration and operation of, the Site, to analyze, customize, optimize and improve the Site, to request feedback, for any purpose for which the information was provided, and as otherwise may be described in this privacy policy.

Personal information provided online may be linked together or merged with other personal information so that we may better understand your needs and inform you about our products or services and those of our partners. In addition, if we receive information from third parties with whom we have business relationships, we may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In either case, this privacy policy governs this information. ****

### COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE SITE

**Newsletters:** We will use your name and email address to send the newsletters and promotional offers to you. If you wish to no longer receive these communications you may follow the unsubscribe mechanism in each of the emails you receive.

**Service-Related Announcements:** We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occassions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspected for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, whic hare not promotional in nature. If you not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactive your account.

### INFORMATION SHARING AND DISCLOSURE

Blog Nation may share your personal information, as well as a record of any transactions you conduct on the Site or offline with us through a third-party advertising partner and its service providers such as Google Mail, Outlook, Mad Mimi, Tumblr, Twitter, and Facebook, which will merge that information with information gathered from other sources in order to deliver to you advertising tailored to your interests when you visit certain websites. Our advertising partner will make the data we provide it anonymous and will only use the data in its anonymized form. Only the intermediary data provider which anonymizes the data comes into contact with any personal information. To choose not to have this information used by our third-party advertising partner, contact us [here](http://www.blognation.com/contact). Please not, this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Blog Nation will not sell or rent your personal information to anyone without your consent, except as expressly disclosed in this privacy policy. Third party advertising partners may use anonymized user information for purposes of publishing Blog Nation advertisements as well as for their own purposes.  

Blog Nation may disclose your personal information (i) with your consent, (ii) to companies who work on behalf of Blog Nation to provide a product or service to you, fulfill your requests, or to assist with the operation of the Site or our business who have agreed not to disclose it to others,(iii) when Blog Nation determines that your actions potentially violate the Blog Nation Terms of Use,or any of our other usage guidelines or rules or (iv) when Blog Nation determines that such action is reasonably necessary to avert or mitigate any action taken by you that is contrary to Blog Nation's interests.  We may in our discretion respond to informal requests for information if we feel that it is in our best interest to do so or to avoid the denigration of third party rights.  We may, but are not required to, give you notice of any disclosure in response to an information request or subpoena. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

Blog Nation may also disclose or transfer information about our users, including personal information, as part of, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition or in any other situation where personal information may be transferred as one of the business assets of Blog Nation.  ****

Blog Nation may disclose any of your information (including personal information and browsing information, to the extent available) to law enforcement, in response to a subpoena, or in the good faith belief that such disclosure is lawfully authorized or required, or that doing so is reasonably necessary or appropriate to respond to claims or to protect the rights, property or safety of Blog Nation, our users, our employees or the public.

### ACCESS TO PERSONAL INFORMATION

If your personal information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delate/deactivate it by making the change in your member information page or contacting us at info@blognation.com. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### SOCIAL MEDIA WIDGETS

Out Web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button [and widgets such as the Share This button or interactive mini-porgrams that run on our site]. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directory on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### SECURITY

Your password is protected for your privacy and security. Blog Nation uses commercially reasonable steps to protect data transmission, but no system is perfect. Therefore, you should carefully safeguard your user name, password, and any log-in information.

Blog Nation stores all personal information on restricted database servers.

If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us at info@blognation.com.

### CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

Blog Nation may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any substantial changes to this policy, we will notify you by posting an announcement on the Site or by any other means reasonably calculated to provide you with actual notice.
